Everybody runs.
Minority Report is a science fiction, action,
thriller film directed by Steven Spielberg.
John Anderton is a top 'Precrime' cop in the late-21st century, when
technology can predict crimes before they're committed.
But Anderton becomes the quarry when another
investigator targets him for a murder charge.
Chief John Anderton, played by Tom Cruise.
Agatha, played by Samantha Morton.
Danny Witwer, played by Colin Farrell.
Director Lamar Burgess, played by Max von Sydow.
Lara Clarke, played by Kathryn Morris.
Jad, played by Steve Harris.
Minority Report is a 2002 American science fiction action thriller film directed by Steven Spielberg
and written by Scott Frank and Jon Cohen, who loosely based the screenplay on Philip K.
Dick's 1956 novella "The Minority Report".
It stars Tom Cruise, Colin Farrell, Samantha Morton, and Max von Sydow.
The film takes place in 2054 in the Washington metropolitan area, where a specialized police "precrime" department
apprehends would-be criminals with the use of foreknowledge provided by three psychics called "precogs".
Minority Report combines elements of the action, sci-fi, tech noir, thriller, and whodunit genres, in addition to being a
traditional chase film, with the main protagonist accused of a crime he has not committed and becoming a fugitive.
Spielberg characterized the story as "50% character and 50% very complicated
storytelling with layers and layers of murder mystery and plot".
The film was first optioned in 1992 as a sequel to another Dick adaptation, Total
Recall (1990), with Arnold Schwarzenegger set to reprise his role.
When Carolco Pictures filed for bankruptcy, the film
was reworked into a standalone project.
Its development started in 1997 after Cohen's
script reached Spielberg and Cruise.
Production suffered multiple delays due to Spielberg's work on A.I.
and Cruise's work on Mission: Impossible 2, both of which ran over schedule.
Spielberg consulted scientists in an attempt to present a more plausible future world than that seen in
other sci-fi films, and some of the film's portrayed technology has proven prescient.
It was produced by 20th Century Fox, DreamWorks Pictures, Cruise/Wagner
Productions, Amblin Entertainment, and Blue Tulip Productions.
20th Century Fox and DreamWorks shared distribution duties.
The high-profile collaboration between Spielberg and Cruise made
Minority Report one of 2002's most anticipated films.
It received positive reviews from critics and was a commercial success,
becoming the year's 10th most successful film worldwide.
It grossed over $358 million on a budget of $102 million.
It was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Sound Editing and won four Saturn Awards (Best Science
Fiction Film, Best Direction, Best Writing, and Best Supporting Actress) from 11 nominations.
It has since been included in lists of the greatest
science fiction films of all time.
The film spawned a tie-in video game in 2002 and a
single-season television series in 2015.
The film explores themes of washington dc, usa, police
chief, precognition, hologram, futuristic.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.